<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Ride</string>
    <string name="custom_dark_map_id">5ad4ac8a37b4bf0e</string>

    <!-- Button text -->
    <string name="record_new_ride_button">RECORD NEW RIDE</string>
    <string name="view_saved_rides_button">VIEW PAST RIDES</string>
    <string name="continue_recording_ride_button">BACK TO CURRENT RIDE</string>
    <string name="start_button">START</string>
    <string name="resume_button">RESUME</string>
    <string name="stop_button">STOP</string>
    <string name="finish_button">FINISH &amp; SAVE</string>
    <string name="exit_view_ride_button">EXIT</string>
    <string name="delete_ride_button">DELETE</string>
    <string name="discard_ride_button_verification">ARE YOU SURE?</string>
    <string name="autopause_button">Autopause</string>

    <string name="dark_map_style_radio_button">\u0020\u0020Dark</string>
    <string name="light_map_style_radio_button">\u0020\u0020Light</string>
    <string name="satellite_map_style_radio_button">\u0020\u0020Satellite</string>
    <string name="hybrid_map_style_radio_button">\u0020\u0020Hybrid</string>
    <string name="imperial_units_radio_button">\u0020\u0020Imperial (miles)</string>
    <string name="metric_units_radio_button">\u0020\u0020Metric (kilometers)</string>

    <!-- TextViews -->
    <string name="distance_title_text">Distance</string>
    <string name="current_speed_title_text">Current Speed</string>
    <string name="average_speed_title_text">Average Speed</string>
    <string name="default_timer_text">00:00</string>
    <string name="autopaused_text">AUTOPAUSED</string>
    <string name="manually_paused_text">STOPPED</string>
    <string name="default_distance_text">0.00</string>
    <string name="no_ride_data_available">- - -</string>
    <string name="no_ride_data_available_text">No ride data available</string>
    <string name="imperial_distance_units">miles</string>
    <string name="imperial_speed_units">mph</string>
    <string name="metric_distance_units">kilometers</string>
    <string name="metric_speed_units">kph</string>
    <string name="finding_location_message">FINDING LOCATION</string>
    <string name="refining_location_message">IMPROVING ACCURACY</string>
    <string name="period">.</string>
    <string name="gps_found">LOCATION FOUND</string>
    <string name="map_style_title">Map Style</string>
    <string name="distance_units_title">Distance Units</string>
    <string name="company_name_attribution">by Jantz Technologies</string>
    <string name="tap_to_continue">Tap anywhere to continue</string>
    <string name="elevation_gain">Elevation Gain</string>
    <string name="elevation_loss">Elevation Loss</string>
    <string name="speed_shading_explanation_red">RED = FAST</string>
    <string name="speed_shading_explanation_purple">PURPLE = SLOW</string>

    <!-- Toolbar titles -->
    <string name="past_rides_title">Home</string>
    <string name="settings_title">Settings</string>
    <string name="statistics_title">Statistics</string>
    <string name="about_title">About / FAQ</string>

    <!-- File names -->
    <string name="ride_folder_prefix">ride_folder_</string>
    <string name="ride_stats_filename">ride_statistics</string>
    <string name="all_locations_filename">all_locations</string>
    <string name="accepted_locations_filename">accepted_locations</string>
    <string name="manual_pause_indices_all_locations_filename">manual_pause_indices_all_locations</string>
    <string name="manual_pause_indices_accepted_locations_filename">manual_pause_indices_accepted_locations</string>
    <string name="route_thumbnail_filename">route_thumbnail</string>

    <string name="settings_folder_name">user_settings</string>
    <string name="autopause_setting_filename">autopause_setting</string>
    <string name="keep_screen_on_setting_filename">keep_screen_on_setting</string>
    <string name="map_type_setting_filename">map_type_setting</string>
    <string name="distance_units_setting_filename">distance_units_setting</string>
    <string name="last_launch_timestamp_filename">last_launch_timestamp</string>

    <!-- intent extra keys -->
    <string name="ride_folder_name">ride folder name</string>
    <string name="enable_back_button">enable back button</string>
    <string name="route_preview">Route preview</string>
    <string name="settings">settings</string>
    <string name="stats_over_time">stats over time</string>

    <!-- GraphView custom attributes (axis labels and titles) -->
    <string name="distance_graph_title">Distance</string>
    <string name="speed_graph_title">Speed</string>
    <string name="elevation_graph_title">Elevation</string>
    <string name="time_graph_title">Time</string>
    <string name="cumulative_distance_graph_title">Cumulative Distance</string>
    <string name="imperial_distance_units_parenthesized">\u0020(mi)</string>
    <string name="imperial_speed_units_parenthesized">\u0020(mph)</string>
    <string name="imperial_elevation_units_parenthesized">\u0020(ft)</string>
    <string name="metric_distance_units_parenthesized">\u0020(km)</string>
    <string name="metric_speed_units_parenthesized">\u0020(kph)</string>
    <string name="metric_elevation_units_parenthesized">\u0020(m)</string>
    <string name="day_units_parenthesized">\u0020(days)</string>

    <!-- statistics activity tabs -->
    <string name="tab_text_week">Last 7 Days</string>
    <string name="tab_text_month">Last 30 Days</string>
    <string name="tab_text_year">Last 365 Days</string>
    <string name="tab_text_full">Full History</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- FAQ / About activity questions and answers -->
    <string name="faq_question_1">What does Ride do and how does it work?</string>
    <string name="faq_answer_1">Ride uses data from satellites, cell towers, and nearby wifi signals
        to track your location during bike rides. These data are then analyzed to provide useful
        analytics to track your performance over time.</string>
    <string name="faq_question_2">What kinds of devices does Ride work on?</string>
    <string name="faq_answer_2">Ride is programmed to work on all smartphones that run Android 5.0
        (Lollipop) or higher. It is not compatible with Android wearOS (smartwatches) or Apple products.</string>
    <string name="faq_question_3">Can Ride be used to track activities other than biking?</string>
    <string name="faq_answer_3">Absolutely. Though the app is marketed towards cyclists, it is capable
        of tracking exercise data across a wide range of speeds, from a stroll to beyond highway speeds.</string>
    <string name="faq_question_4">How accurate are location data?</string>
    <string name="faq_answer_4">"The short answer is \"typically within several meters\". However, there is "
        "variation in location accuracy that hinges on several factors. First, different devices may vary in their "
        "location accuracy. Second, physical obstructions wreak havoc on your phone's ability to receive and process "
        "satellite signals. Therefore, this app is not conducive to indoor activity tracking or even certain outdoor "
        "activities such as spelunking, scuba diving, digging a hole to China, etc."</string>
    <string name="faq_question_5">I\'m having issues recording rides. What should I do?</string>
    <string name="faq_answer_5">"There are two main issues that often hinder Ride\'s "
        "performance during recording sessions. First, users sometimes leave their phones on power saving "
        "mode, which saves power by restricting background tasks such as satellite signal processing. As "
        "a result, the phone stops calculating its location when you turn off the screen, ruining the "
        "recording session. Second, on more recent Android OS versions, users are allowed to set background "
        "usage limits for different apps. To ensure that you didn\'t inadvertently limit Ride's background "
        "usage, go to Settings and search \"sleeping apps\". Make sure that Ride is not in the list of sleeping "
        "apps or deep sleeping apps, and the operating system will be far less likely to kill your "
        "recording session."</string>
    <string name="faq_question_6">How private is my data? Do you sell it to anyone?</string>
    <string name="faq_answer_6"> Satellite signals are terrible for elevation calculations, so the app
        sends the coordinates of points along your ride to a trusted open-source elevation database, opentopodata.org,
        to ask for the accompanying elevation data for each location. Elevation gain/loss statistics can then
        be calculated using this information. However, this is the only external use of your personal data and
        its only purpose is to provide you with more accurate ride statistics. Jantz Technologies does
        not store, track, sell, or profit from ANY of your data in any way.</string>
    <string name="faq_question_7">Who created this app?</string>
    <string name="faq_answer_7">Ride was programmed by David Jantz in 2021 with full copyright protections.</string>
    <string name="faq_question_8">I love Ride! How can I support your work?</string>
    <string name="faq_answer_8">Whether you love Ride as is or have suggestions for improvement, your
       feedback is valuable. If you find a glitch in the performance of the app, that is an especially
       high priority for me! Feel free to leave kudos or advice in a review on the Google Play Store.
       I DO read reviews :)</string>
    <string name="faq_question_9">I have a question that isn\'t answered on this page. Where can I
       find answers?</string>
    <string name="faq_answer_9">Send an email to jantztechnologies@gmail.com. Do keep in mind that this
        app is a passion project unsupported by ad revenue. As such, I may not get back to you in a timely
        manner.</string>

</resources>